<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ScrollingApp</string>
    <string name="article_title">Guinea Pigs</string>
    <string name="article_text">Guinea pig, (Cavia porcellus),(https://www.britannica.com/animal/guinea-pig) a domesticated species of South American rodent belonging to the cavy family (Caviidae). It resembles other cavies in having a robust body with short limbs, large head and eyes, and short ears. The feet have hairless soles and short sharp claws. There are four toes on the forefeet and three on the hind feet. Several breeds of domesticated guinea pigs exist, which are sometimes grouped by coat texture and hair length. The term guinea pig is also used colloquially to refer to a person who serves as a test subject in an experiment.Among rodents, domestic guinea pigs are fairly large, weighing 500 to 1,500 grams (roughly 1 to 3 pounds) and having a body 20 to 40 cm (8 to 16 inches) long. The tail is not visible externally. There is a crest of longer hairs at the neck, but length and texture of the fur vary from smooth (short or long) to coarse and short or long and silky. Coloration is extremely variable: the coat may be white, cream, tan, reddish or chocolate brown, black, or a combined pattern.\n\n
    Guinea pigs eat vegetation and do not require water to drink if supplied with sufficiently moist food, but they must have water if fed dry commercial food. They breed all year in captivity. Females bear up to 13 young per litter (4 is average); gestation takes 68 days. Although the young can scamper about and eat solid food the day they are born, they are not fully weaned for about three weeks. Females mature in two months, males in three, and captive guinea pigs live up to eight years, although three to five is typical.
    No natural population of this species exists in the wild. Guinea pigs were apparently domesticated more than 3,000 years ago in Peru, coinciding with humans’ transition from a nomadic to an agricultural lifestyle. The Incas kept guinea pigs, and the animals were bred during the same period by various people who lived along the Andes Mountains from northwestern Venezuela to central Chile. These rodents remain a sustainable food source for the native peoples of Ecuador, Peru, and Bolivia, who either keep them in their homes or allow them to scavenge freely both indoors and out. Guinea pigs were taken to Europe in the 16th century, and since the 1800s they have been popular as pets. They are also used internationally as laboratory animals for studies of anatomy, nutrition, genetics, toxicology, pathology, serum development, and other research programs.

    </string>
    <string name="article_subtitle">What are guinea pigs?</string>
</resources>